And I've got the regular schedule to make my city council for two days December 6, 2020, but I'm two, but let's get to the first one.
Parents of this have none.
3A, post-flation from my own area economic development services Mr. Gandiron.
I should have been very, very quick.
Merry Christmas.
I'll give you our comment.
We're just happy to have us to take with us to San Antonio in February.
Basically, what we've been doing over the last couple of weeks is getting on the way running on a demographic or a gap in Alice.
Because what those things tell us is the same business as a looking at.
If there's enough business there, usually gap in Alice's before, we can certainly at any time you won't come by.
What it tells us is, if you give them more, if you give them reach out of category, how much we're currently selling, what we're missing out on.
In particular, category, in other words, that's the gap.
What's leaving to go to some other community to purchase those same goods and services.
And that number, that difference, is what businesses will look at determine if you're a community.
gap in Alice, it tells us where we will read, and that's where we need to talk.
That's where we need to be.
Does that mean we're going to turn anybody else away that wants to come in and invest money into it?
It just means that we're now spreading out through the created.
We want to recruit our best.
So that's what we've been working on.
Great team that will strategy is that's working on this.
We've been here before too long, certainly before.
project, which that money, because I too that we met with a potential restaurant business
downtown, two weeks ago, so I didn't have it, and Shannon pulled that crap out, so
it's up on his phone.
I just got in at that day.
It's got to ask me a question, because what you didn't do?
You guys have a real beat?
Actually, yes, you do.
I mean, it's that quick.
I'm sure to do a guy in the guy.
I was like, yeah, I just think like, can you send me that?
Yeah, yeah.
So, and we're still talking to him, and I think we're going to go forward with him.
It's good stuff.
But what's the option that you're sorry to get it to you?
But I'll send you some cool things.
The updated demographic.
I don't know what to see.
He has a place for AI.
You can put it over a quest.
Thank you.
Hello, Abishan.
Can you just say a shot?
A shot.
Second.
Barns.
High.
East.
Jones.
Double.
High.
Parker.
4B.
Minutes from the December 2nd.
25th.
Right.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Double.
High.
Jones.
Barns.
Parker.
Four C.
Vote to enter into contract with Flock Safety.
For automatic license plate where you're cameras,
you can continue to pump on a legal and find out
to review you all prizes and manage your design.
Two things.
So this is the continuation of the grant that I've talked about
for the last couple of months.
Six more cameras.
Besides what you want to give.
No.
I'm getting 10.
Block cameras.
And this is fixed.
That's too much live stream.
Every single location where there's a block hammer.
Over the live stream.
Had no extra.
No extra.
Sweet.
A link in the description.
A group.
Second.
Parker.
Go.
Five.
Jones.
East.
All right.
I would also just like to take that out of the sign of this.
The.
What you gave a couple months ago for the in-car cameras.
That is such a process.
Thank you.
Okay.
So these are.
The ordinances that.
The old family.
Rex Center.
All air hockey or pinball titles are maintained or any combination for profit, but it's not a pool hall.
That's a different one.
So this is another set of ordinances that will then recommend that we reveal as being out there and it will help with the
key ordinance to have it more out today at the moment.
You'll go up 10 years.
It's been for most of you this time.
Can we do you want to visit correct?
Yes, sir.
Okay, so looking for a motion on out of D, ordinance 20.5-20 forward.
Motion.
5-27 Revealing Section 12-1-29
Motion to Proved.
Second.
So call.
5.
Jo.
Perfect.
5.
4-8.
4-205-28.
Revealing Section 12-1-30.
Motion to Proved.
Second.
So call.
5.
Jo.
4.
it's 2025-29,000,000 section 12 that's around 3-1.
Let's take it.
Don't call.
He's step 5.
Jones and Barnside Parker.
4J.
Ordinance 2025-30,000.
30,000,000,000.
12,000,000.
1,3,000.
Oh, sure.
Second.
Don't call.
He's step 5.
Jones and Barnside Parker.
4K.
Ordinance 2025-31,000.
5,000.
4,000.
Jones.
Burns.
5,000.
4,000.
Ordinance 2025-32.
And then the employee retirement system, five benefit plan.
What's in your mind?
That's pretty.
Thank you for having me.
Your time.
To your cough drop?
No.
I got a few, but I do appreciate it.
No worries.
And happy to be here to talk to you tonight about your retirement plans.
The city of Miami has participated in the open home and used for a time of fun for approximately 10 years now.
And in that 10 years, I have a proud to say, I have never had to come back to this council to say, you need to contribute more money to your plan.
In fact, since you have joined, you have been able to give two major plan upgrades and your costs have still been coming down.
So with that in mind, keep in mind the number, 13.2% because that is approximately what the city contributes into the retirement system.
So I gave an actual study inside this folder and I want to go over to the fourth page back that looks like this.
Okay.
Tonight, you are in the position of where being caused, you have been diligent in how you've come to the plan.
You have the ability that you can award or do and upgrade in your plan.
And once again, it will not cost any new dollars.
So currently, you're on plan level BB.
The employees contribute 4.5% and they'll require a rate by the city of 7.12.
However, you are contributing approximately 13.2%.
So you are over funding your retirement plan.
And what we're proposing tonight is because of that funding policy, you can move up to plan level AA.
The employees currently would stay at 4.5%.
And then in July, we were present a plan of inland to increase their contribution rate to five and a quarter.
And so the city would contribute the nine, actually, it's a little bit more than that.
It's a, a, a, a, a, a, a 10 point four o percent, okay?
Again, still approximately three percentage points less than what you are actually contributing.
Go over to the next page, what's like this.
When you started with going more of your retirement system, it was approximately 65 percent funded.
As of this, most recent, actual, aerial study, you are now 88 percent funded.
So your funding level has come up dramatically, and that's with the two upgrades that you've given.
So if the one down the current plan of what column, you of your plan is $9.9 million to retiree survivors and deferred VISTAs, people out of pinch and just not collecting.
You of $7.8 million to your active employees and the total liability is $17.7 million.
As of July 1st of 24, you had $15.6 million in the bank.
So your unfunded liability was $2.165 million.
If you choose to do the plan level increase, notice the increase, only affect your active employee group that does not affect any of your retirees.
And so the liability for your active employee group would increase to $1.5.3 million.
So the total liability then would be $19 million.
You still have your $15.6 on the bank, so your liability would now be $3.4 million.
But again, you are over funding your plan in an effort to try to pay that liability down.
And so we project that over time, it will pay off substantially quicker than what we project in here and we project in here 25 years.
But it will pay down substantially quicker than that.
The reason that this improvement is a big deal for your employee group, this represents a 16 and 23% increase in retirement benefit for them.
So it is not in consequential.
And I've worked with Tyler and the folks in HR over the years to try and make sure that whenever we presented a plan upgrade, it was fairly affordable.
And the cause of the way you have continued to fund your plan and upgrade like this is definitely this really affordable.
So, what questions may I answer for you?
Historically, it's affordable, meaning we won't have an increase at all authority at the 15%.
That's correct.
That is not only what you don't have an increase,
we'll still need over 100% of your plans.
And I'm projecting that, if you look at this block here, that 9.9A,
what's what page is that?
It's on that second page.
That is that 9.9A.
As your plan asks, as your liability pays down,
the project that your total cost will trend downward
to that 9.9A total.
Well, remember, out that number of your employees
are going to be doing five or four.
And so, the city's contribution, right?
Think of it like a snowball.
It's just building and building and building and building
to pay that liability off that much faster.
So, the hope is with us keeping the overfunded
that we can eventually move up to another plan,
because the better, the better retirement we have for the employees
and your desirable place is to work on the moving
to our increased employees to come here.
If I put you in context of your communities around here,
but the need and the water are on a double end trip away.
So, they're already a higher plan.
We're just that remaining percentage goes
of the European Court, too.
How are those paid off the assets?
Yeah, what happens is it builds your asset base.
So, there are several things that will affect your asset base.
If you have...
turn over on non-vested employees. Basically the liability that's associated with the non-vested
employee gets wiped off the books if they leave. So the assets that you would pay in it just
becomes bonus contributions and brings your unfunded liability down that much quicker. If you
overfund the plan, that builds your asset base. If Tyler is a really, really nice guy and he's going
to avoid 10% raises to the employee group this year. But if you want. But if you want, they
like that will actually hurt your liability. So it's going to get through though. We assume
that the plan or that the city will be a prairie since every single year, but you get higher
than expected prairies. It hurts your plans if you give lower than expected prairies. It actually
helps your plan. Don't tell me that. So it's not just the matter of the building the asset base,
the things that will affect that asset base due to demographic factors. We also assume that the
investment since I have a plan makes seven or four percent. And over the last 10 years we are worth
that 8 percent. So we have definitely done that. In fact when we look at ourselves and we compare ourselves
nationwide to other public BB plans, we're actually scoring in the top third to the top 25%
depending on the time of the time of the time horizon given. So the assets are being managed in a very
creative way to make sure that they're growing in excess of that seven or four. I think for this
year, this year, this for count calendar year, we're at approximately 13 percent rate of return. There's
still time to screw that up because there's still days left in the year. But overall the plan asset
does do the investment side have actually been very good. And whenever that happens, basically that means
that the city does not have to contribute as much money to the point. The analogy that I typically
give is the visibility on your plan is like a mortgage in your house. And what we all do whenever we buy
our home is we all pay that $100 or that $200 extra on our house payment to build our equity
so that in 5, 6, 7, 8 years due to appreciation and extra that we've paid in, we can upgrade to a bigger
better house and it doesn't cost us any money to do so. And that concept actually applies to your
requirements of the extreme wealth. And that's the position.
No, no, no, I have another question, and this is probably a dumb question, I was trying
to look under our charter.
If far-responsibility is as counsel in the mayor, don't extend beyond the powers of the
city manager, why are we affecting or having any kind of involvement over their retirement
plan?
So that's what the employer does, the employer provides the benefit packet.
I think we sometimes, we don't hire employees, we don't discipline employees.
Yeah, it's just looking in our charter at our kind of what our powers and lack of powers
are, and some of those talk about, obviously, we can't go and tell an employee what to
do.
So, I'm just, and like I said, maybe it's a dumb question, but...
Well, you've been the city, and you've used all things, make financial decisions, over a set
amount, certainly not to this extent, without counsel or approval.
Okay.
That's all I wanted to say.
There's more of a money thing than an employee thing, but you do run the company that employees
are employees.
I'll just double check it.
I was very skeptical at first, because I thought, you know, somebody's going to pay for it, it's
either, and I even want as far as to tell Cindy, I need to figure out if I have a conflict, because
either the city's going to pay for it, or the employees who my M1 is going to pay for it,
and then Chris explained it to me, and it's a good deal.
Again, just...
And so, your plan is enacted by four to the same city.
Okay.
Oh, that makes sense, then.
Thank you for that clarification.
Okay.
Second.
All right.
Jones.
He said, double.
All right.
Jones.
Now, for M, as a march you clause, this one is going to be just...
Right.
Yes.
And the reason I was also skeptical as to whether what to do it is an emergency, but I
compare the statute with the reason for it, and the reason is to prevent disruption of employee
benefit coverage, and that would be that would qualify as an emergency.
Most approved
are being or these block 24.
Correct.
So the burden of recognition of the city,
zoning and planning to make sure that we're hearing that through.
Approved that ordinance to reason those two particular properties from their
current zoning are in two.
To request and recommend it to them, we're learning what these properties.
They get very dilapidated houses on this.
Paying the properties and spent the necessary dollars to make those.
You can't say that's what it's like.
What they plan to construct properties like some properties and
conduct objectives had some plans printed.
So you'll see what they plan on.
They really, really, really, really, really.
Mine, the power of the need to do housing.
So, about the post office?
No, it's my nine tribes tower for us.
Thank you, sir.
So it's gonna take two, you'll have to let me just try to mend the eight, basically two of those, all the doors.
So each unit's like 600 square feet about there?
They're about?
550, yeah. Well, I came up with the 546. Sorry.
That's amazing.
Chris, have you looked over these points?
I've reviewed the drawings, we haven't necessarily entirely reviewed those plans, but I did briefly.
And in my quick review, I didn't see any of these.
The only thing that is a small hiccup right now is the number of required marketing spaces that he has to develop.
I was just getting ready to ask about parking, especially in that area.
Yes, he's going to be required to do 12 new parking spaces, and he's technically only has room for change.
So I believe he's maybe considering a possible variance request for those two.
That's a good.
Okay.
I would say to have seen some of the projects that this couple have done with some other buildings that they remodeled.
I did great work.
So we appreciate that.
We appreciate you guys helping me clean up my aluminum house.
Just do the one on the truck route.
Cool.
Good.
Let's take a second.
More she can take a second.
Hi.
Four.
Oh.
What is 255-34 for the rezoning?
I think it's a little bit different.
It's a little bit different.
It's actually an existing structure that he knows turning to pressure.
At one point in time there was kind of like an additional add-on or a garage apartment that was attached to kind of the northeast corridor, this existing house.
The middle section completely dilapidated.
So he wants to take the opportunity to kind of separate those two and make two dwellings on one property, which obviously requires the R and two-selling from its current R and five.
That's my area.
I like the idea that kind of look at that.
Here's about there anyway.
So I like it.
I'll make the motion to approve.
Second.
Five.
Eastern.
All right.
Jones.
Furnst.
Parker.
Again, thank you guys.
We appreciate you.
Best of the mile.
Thank you.
I'm five A, nomination to the points for any Wilson to the MIMA,
a convention of Visitor's Bureau, a placing set of a quick turn through
the Spire 11, 2021 and 27.
Most proof?
Second.
A step.
Aye.
Furns.
Jones.
I'm staying.
I'm six.
It was the third problem.
I'm seven.
Another new business.
If any of this is posted this agenda, eight A, and eight B,
or staff reports.
I'm nine.
They're, counseled to me to do that.
Yes.
There's a sip and shop this week.
There's a lot.
All Thursday.
Be there.
There's square.
Four to seven.
Is there alcohol?
Is there?
In.
There's goodies.
There's some treats.
Don't treat.
Did you just saw that?
I'm not concerned.
I know others are.
Oh.
I'm just asking.
As a child.
Yes.
No, sir.
Nope.
I want to say thank you.
City staff.
Once again.
The guys are killing us.
And downtown looks great.
It's up there.
The mandatory lying was fabulous.
And the Christmas parade was, that's what we've had.
And at least 20 years, we know.
But the reason why I want to say thank you the most is because of the kids' faces.
I saw both of those events.
Those kids would have been blasts because of your artwork.
And your people's artwork.
Thank you for taking time away from your regular duty.
Do something that's not somewhat normal on your schedule.
It's making a difference.
And on top of that, you know, the check-stop.
Big set of Christmas programs used the gymnasium in six hundred.
This civic toys.
Once again, we saw parents that had smiles on their faces.
So because of the work, you got to put them to help the tables set up.
They're going to buy it.
It truly takes the community to support the community.
And I'm so proud to serve this way.
And you guys reinforce that one day every day.
So I greatly appreciate all your efforts.
Keep doing what you're doing.
We're done great.
And you're the reason why I was coming back.
We get the easy part up here.
But you and the boys are why my mom was making a comeback.
So thank you.
Thank you very much.
Two things.
I want to make a call to introduce a new sign.
We have a main street.
Or not main but sea villains in the term fight.
Main is really cool.
You know, some of the board voted on, but I got it up to day, right, Kevin, and it's really, really neat, so everybody look at it.
It looks good.
So, second thing is just to wish everybody happy holidays.
You know, we have Christmas coming up, and then we have the ball drop coming up.
So, it'll be good.
So, let's say the ball drop.
If I can, that was something new.
We decided to try this year.
But I don't know how it's going to go.
We don't know.
We did a tree light, though, and it's not many people sort of that first year,
and it's grown every year.
So, we're hoping this ball drop could be a family fun adventure.
That's not a casino, that's not a bar.
You know, the family's can actually come to the hallway.
The ball drop.
So, I hope everybody comes.
And then a number 11, we are not going to go into exactly the session.
So, that will be in 12, 13, and 14.
So, we're not into exactly the session.
So, we will not do any of those.
15 is no action from the executive session.
So, we're 16.
Motion.
Thank you.
All right.
Each step.
I'm going to sign for a record.
All right.
Thank you.